Yogesh kumar garg C communication & permanent address:

1145, majestic tower, mahagun mascot, crossing republic, and ghaziabad- 201016 contact no: 9773914364, 9811144364

email: garg\_yk@yahoo.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yogesh-garg-

437a6121/

## Key credentials:

Having over 30 years of experience of heading the finance and compliance of public sector, business groups and autonomous organizations as the cfo and chief compliance officer. Having over a 30-year experience of working as controller of finance, cost control. Resource mobilization, working capital management business planning, budgeting, taxation management, funding within country from various resources as well as foreign funding, audit, legal management and compliance under various corporate and lab our laws and company secretary affairs.

## M ajor skills & responsibilities

Heading finance & accounts, legal affairs & cs matters and facilitating the delivery of a strong corporate governance framework that maximizes profitability & meets stakeholder expectations while working with reputed psus (mmtc), pvt. Sector companies presently working with sybly group of companies, muradnagar, asgroup head of finance, legal and company secretary.

#### Professional qualification

Degree/ course	University	Year	
B.com. (hons.)	Agra university	1986	
L.I.b.	Lucknow university	1991	
Cost & management accountant (fcma)	Institute of cost accountants of india (icai)	1995	
Fellow member (fcs)	Institute of company secretaries of india (icsi)	1996	
Ca final (group one)	Institute of chartered accountants of india (icai)	1994	

#### Other:

	certificate course on forensic audit from icsi, new delhi
	Certificate course on intellectual property right from fiicci, new delhi certificate
	course on arbitration law, law sikho new delhi
	Diploma on consumer law and practice from national law school, bangalore practical aspect of
П	ind as, ifrs from caclunindia.com
	Certificate course on treasury and international banking from icmai, kolkata
	certificate courses on investment management from icmai, kolkata forensic
	accounting profession from india forensic.com
	Anti – money laundering certification from india forensic.com

# Work experience: -

Organization	Designation	Period	Major responsibility
Own CONSULTANCY	Self	Nov 2020 onwards	
Renaissance group of companies,	Group cfo cum company secretary	. 7feb 2020 to31oct 2020	Delhi the group has multiple entities of various public limited, pvt limited, llp, partnership, trust, and holdings and subsidies. Looking after all finance. Legal, secretarial and taxation, Etc. (turnover rs 1000 crore)
M/s accurate Group (group having np of companies including listed entity and educational institute) noida	Sr. Consultant	IST JULY 2016 TO 31 <sup>ST</sup> DEC 2019	As a consultant of finance/ secretarial, legal was responsible for all accounts finance, audit, legal, labor laws secretarial, compliance, looking after finalization of account, taxation, gst, audit, income tax matter, and assessment & appeal.
VENKATESHWARA UNIVERSITY	FINANCE OFFICER	5 TH JUNE 2013 TO 31 ST DEC 2015	HEAD OF FINANCE OF UNIVERSITY
Nsc Itd Delhi	Gm finance cum company secretary	22/oct2010 3/June 2013	As head of finance/ secretarial, legal was responsible for all accounts finance, audit, legal, labor laws secretarial, compliance, looking after finalization of account, taxation, gst, audit, income tax matter, And assessment & appeal.
Cel	Agm (finance)	09/01/2010 To 21/10/2010	As head of finance was responsible for all accounts finance, audit, legal, labor laws secretarial, compliance, looking after finalization of account, taxation, gst, audit, income tax matter,  And assessment & appeal
Institute of chartered accountants of India new Delhi	Dy director	29/06/2007 to 23/12/2008	Ceo of icai accounting research foundation a section 25 company
Nstfdc	Manager finance	16/05/2006 to 29/06/2007	Head of finance and accounts

Mmtc Itd (cpsu) Delhi/Lucknow/Kolkata	Manager (f&a)	14/oct 1996 - 15/may 2006	Management of funds on all India bases with various regional offices spread all over India and submission of the report to management on export of iron ore. Posted at h.o. in the banking division and maintenance of bank accounts. (turnover rs 50000 cr)
Somiya organics Itd barabanki	Manager (accounts )	18/05/1996 to 12/101996	Head of account banking, accounts, payroll, finalization, income tax, sale Tax, pf esi etc.
Apace leasing and finance It	Finance executive	16/10.1992 to 30/05/1995	Head of account banking, accounts, payroll, finalization, income tax, sale Tax, pf esi etc.

# **Membership**

Fellow of institute of cost accountants of India
Fellow of institute of company secretary of India
Member of all India bar council and Delhi bar council
Member of certified fraud organization (acfe, USA)
Member of cima UK.

Computer	efficiency	,
Computer	CITICICITY Y	

Tally accounting package.

Ms office and internet applications.

Management information systems.

Various erp packages like sap, Microsoft Navision, fact and other custom software packages according to organization requirement

Training- training on board orientation, sap, erp, investment, international banking, intellectual property, ind as, international taxation, arbitration, gst, treasury management, consumer protection Law, forensic audit, contact management, corporate governance practice, fema,

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 04/02/1967

Language : Hindi,

English